<?xml version="1.0"?>
<xmlMandatorySingleRootNode copyright="Broadcom Corporation, 2012" >




<object name="InternetGatewayDevice." shortObjectName="FakeParentObject" specSource="Broadcom" profile="Unspecified" requirements="P" supportLevel="Present" />
  <description source="BROADCOM">This is a fake object node for the DataModelDesigner to draw the object hierarchy properly.  It will not be inserted into the data model.   The Short Object Name must be FakeParentObject. </description>




<object name="InternetGatewayDevice.Device." shortObjectName="FakeParentObject" specSource="Broadcom" profile="Unspecified" requirements="P" supportLevel="Present" />
  <description source="BROADCOM">This is a fake object node for the DataModelDesigner to draw the object hierarchy properly.  It will not be inserted into the data model.   The Short Object Name must be FakeParentObject. </description>




<object name="InternetGatewayDevice.Device.InterfaceStack.{i}." shortObjectName="Dev2InterfaceStackObject" specSource="TR181" profile="Device2_Baseline:1" requirements="R" supportLevel="MultipleInstances" oid="1060" />
  <description source="TRx">This table contains information about the relationships between the multiple layers of interface objects ([Section 4.3/TR-181i2]). In particular, it contains information on which interfaces run on top of which other interfaces.&#10;&#10;&#10;&#10;This table is auto-generated by the CPE based on the LowerLayers parameters on individual interface objects.&#10;&#10;&#10;&#10;Each table row represents a &quot;link&quot; between two interface objects, a higher-layer interface object (referenced by HigherLayer) and a lower-layer interface object (referenced by LowerLayer). Consequently, if a referenced interface object is deleted, the CPE MUST delete the corresponding InterfaceStack row(s) that had referenced it.&#10;&#10;&#10;&#10;At most one entry in this table can exist with the same values for HigherLayer and LowerLayer, or with a given value for Alias.</description>

  <parameter name="Alias" type="string" specSource="TR181" profile="Unspecified" requirements="W" mayDenyActiveNotification="true" denyActiveNotification="true" supportLevel="ReadWrite" defaultValue="cpe-intfstack" maxLength="64" autoGenerateAlias="true" />
    <description source="TRx">	A non-volatile handle used to reference this instance. Alias provides a mechanism for an ACS to label this instance for future reference.&#10;&#10;&#10;&#10;If the CPE supports the Alias-based Addressing feature as defined in [Section 3.6.1/TR-069a4] and described in [Appendix II/TR-069a4], the following mandatory constraints MUST be enforced:&#10;&#10;&#10;&#10;    Its value MUST NOT be empty.&#10;&#10;    Its value MUST start with a letter.&#10;&#10;    If its instance object is created by the CPE, the initial value MUST start with a &quot;cpe-&quot; prefix.&#10;&#10;    The CPE MUST NOT change the parameter value. </description>

  <parameter name="HigherLayer" type="string" specSource="TR181" profile="Device2_Baseline:2" requirements="R" supportLevel="ReadOnly" maxLength="256" alwaysWriteToConfigFile="true" />
    <description source="TRx">A reference to the interface object corresponding to the higher layer of the relationship, i.e. the interface which runs on top of the interface identified by the corresponding instance of LowerLayer.&#10;&#10;&#10;&#10;When the referenced higher layer interface is deleted, the CPE MUST delete the table row.</description>

  <parameter name="LowerLayer" type="string" specSource="TR181" profile="Device2_Baseline:2" requirements="R" supportLevel="ReadOnly" maxLength="256" alwaysWriteToConfigFile="true" />
    <description source="TRx">A reference to the interface object corresponding to the lower layer of the relationship, i.e. the interface which runs below the interface identified by the corresponding instance of HigherLayer.&#10;&#10;&#10;&#10;When the referenced lower layer interface is deleted, the CPE MUST delete the table row.</description>

  <parameter name="HigherAlias" type="string" specSource="TR181" profile="Unspecified" requirements="R" supportLevel="ReadOnly" maxLength="64" alwaysWriteToConfigFile="true" />
    <description source="TRx">The value of the Alias parameter for the interface object referenced by HigherLayer.</description>

  <parameter name="LowerAlias" type="string" specSource="TR181" profile="Unspecified" requirements="R" supportLevel="ReadOnly" maxLength="64" alwaysWriteToConfigFile="true" />
    <description source="TRx">The value of the Alias parameter for the interface object referenced by LowerLayer.</description>


<vsaInfo>

<validstringarray name="minimumSingleVsaValues" />
  <element>IgnoreThis</element>

</vsaInfo>



<profileInfo>
<profile name="Device2_Baseline:1" /> 
<profile name="Device2_Baseline:2" /> 
<profile name="Device2_Baseline:3" /> 
<profile name="Unspecified" /> 
</profileInfo>


</xmlMandatorySingleRootNode>
